<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Marius Constantinescu</title>
  <subtitle>Tech blog</subtitle>
  <id>https://mariusc.github.io/</id>
  <link href="https://mariusc.github.io/"/>
  <link href="https://mariusc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-01-22T22:56:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Conferences are not dead</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2018-01-22-conferences-are-not-dead.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2018-01-22-conferences-are-not-dead.html</id>
    <published>2018-01-22T22:56:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read Chris Adamson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://subfurther.com/blog/2018/01/15/the-final-conf-down/"&gt;post on conferences&lt;/a&gt; last week. A few hours later, I also found Marco Arment&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://marco.org/2018/01/17/end-of-conference-era"&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt;. And Friday afternoon, Dave Verwer also &lt;a href="https://iosdevweekly.com/issues/335#start"&gt;wrote about this&lt;/a&gt; in his newsletter, which drew even more attention to this topic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all three make some great points, there&amp;rsquo;s one thing which I completely disagree with: conferences are not a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lascorbe"&gt;Luis&lt;/a&gt; maintain this &lt;a href="https://github.com/Lascorbe/CocoaConferences"&gt;list of conferences&lt;/a&gt; for almost 2 years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping my eyes on all iOS-related conferences out there for at least double than that time. I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in one conference every year since 2015 and I&amp;rsquo;ve watched lots of videos and followed a lot of the buzz around them on Twitter. &lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s the end of the conference era.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure, lots of conferences have ceased to exist. But new ones appeared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started looking into iOS development, &lt;a href="http://nsconference.com/"&gt;NSConference&lt;/a&gt; was one of the biggest and best conferences out there. NSConf had its last edition in 2015. But other great conferences appeared, like &lt;a href="htt[s://nsspain.com"&gt;NSSpain&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://mobileera.rocks"&gt;Mobile Era&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://addconf.com"&gt;ADDC&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.appbuilders.ch/"&gt;AppBuilders&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://theswiftalps.com/"&gt;The Swift Alps&lt;/a&gt;. You may notice that all those are in Europe. That&amp;rsquo;s probably because I know more about the conferences in Europe than the ones in the US or elsewhere. Or because there are actually more conferences in Europe than in the US (which the 2 other blog posts seem to be focused on).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, counting the conferences that are already announced for 2018, we have 28 iOS-only conferences and 16 mobile-related conferences, and there are many others which will take place but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been announced for 2018 (Looking at you, NSSpain, Pragma Conf, Swift Alps, try! Swift India, try! Swift NYC, AltConf and others). I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s few. Sure, CocoaConf stopping is a big loss for the US conference scene, but overall, I think there are still a lot of good events all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;My thoughts exactly. I feel the mobile / iOS conference ecosystem in Europe is the largest it has ever been &lt;a href="https://t.co/9u3IqvQ3Gv"&gt;https://t.co/9u3IqvQ3Gv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Aleksandar Vacić (@radiantav) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/radiantav/status/954279099693961218?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago people went to conferences to hear the talks. Now almost all the presentations are recorded and you can watch them from home. The main advantage of going to conferences nowadays is talking to face to face to other people in your line of work. There are lots of opportunities. New collaborations can start, which lead to &lt;a href="https://www.objc.io/books/app-architecture/"&gt;great books being published&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Without Andyy, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I would&amp;rsquo;ve met &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cocoawithlove?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@cocoawithlove&lt;/a&gt; in person, and we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have started this. Conferences can be pretty useful, if only for bringing people together. Thanks Andyy ❤️ &lt;a href="https://t.co/2KJre51Fhf"&gt;https://t.co/2KJre51Fhf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chris Eidhof (@chriseidhof) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriseidhof/status/954392456157687808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You make new friends at a conference. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;My favorite part about being in the iOS community is getting to meet people all around the world! Thanks Oscar for the awesome time 😊 &lt;a href="https://t.co/4QQIbF4caI"&gt;https://t.co/4QQIbF4caI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kristina Fox ⌚️ (@krstnfx) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/krstnfx/status/954487594439540736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know people who got new jobs after attending conferences. I know people who got new contracts, new clients after conferences. Conferences are nice :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yes, they&amp;rsquo;re not perfect. There are problems. They&amp;rsquo;re expensive, they usually lack diversity (both in speakers and in participants), most of them have the same speakers, some even giving the same talk to multiple conferences. Some people say that due to the speakers being mostly the same at all conferences, some kind of &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; is created, which does not help the community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, try to see the things from the perspective of the organizers. I&amp;rsquo;ve organized summer schools for around 70 student attendees in Romania, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to organize CocoaHeads Bucharest. It&amp;rsquo;s hard. You don&amp;rsquo;t find people who want to give talks that easily. And it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of effort and you need to spend a lot of time to make an event. Now try to think of the scale of a conference. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work involved in making a conference. And let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to start a new one. If you bring all new speakers, people will be reluctant to attend because they haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of any of the ones giving the talks. If you bring speakers who already have a reputation, you can be criticised for lacking diversity. All those critiques have a high impact on your morale, which again won&amp;rsquo;t help with the organization of the event. And imagine doing this for years and years in a row. There&amp;rsquo;s no wonder some conferences stop having new editions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with all this effort required to make a conference, the number of events (at least in Europe) is growing. So hats off to you 🙇, conference organizers everywhere! Thank you for giving us opportunities to meet each other and learn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard developers saying they go to conferences mostly for the people and the experience, and not for the talks. Many seem to agree that the &amp;ldquo;hallway track&amp;rdquo; is at least as important as the actual talks. So it&amp;rsquo;s clear that at least in this direction, conferences need to improve. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to say how, but some of them are trying. The Swift Alps is a different kind of conference, with a &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@swiftalps/the-concept-behind-the-swift-alps-5b07e04c7ed1"&gt;unique concept&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to participate yet, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to, and I&amp;rsquo;ve heard good things about it. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s the way to &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; conferences, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a step forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think conferences are dead. There are more now than before. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list to inspire you: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Lascorbe/CocoaConferences"&gt;https://github.com/Lascorbe/CocoaConferences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making a conference is hard and expensive. Which explains why some of them stop. And why we should be more appreciative of their organizers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many things at conferences that can be improved, and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know how. But some conferences are already trying (The Swift Alps, Swift Aveiro).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What this WWDC means for us</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2017-07-21-what-this-wwdc-means-for-us.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2017-07-21-what-this-wwdc-means-for-us.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-21T23:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This article was first published on the &lt;a href="https://engineering.nodesagency.com/articles/iOS/What-this-WWDC-means-for-us/"&gt;Nodes Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt; in June 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-laravel.vapor.cloud/image/nstack/translate_values/wwdc17-og_gKPiuvwlII.jpg"/ width = 100%&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WWDC 2017 happened at the beginning of June in San Jose, California, and Apple presented lots of exciting changes. We already covered in &lt;a href="https://www.nodesagency.com/ios-11-top-new-features-additions/"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; the most important iOS additions from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective, but what exactly did WWDC 2017 bring for an iOS developer? Continuing the trend from the last year, the WWDC Keynote was less targeted to developers, and more towards media and users. The interesting things for developers are covered mostly in the Platforms State of the Union, and in the following sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="swift-4"&gt;Swift 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was expected, iOS 11 comes with Swift 4. However, since Swift is open source, and all the development is done in the open, there were no big surprises here. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/olebegemann"&gt;Ole Begemann&lt;/a&gt; made a playground a few weeks before WWDC showing &lt;a href="https://oleb.net/blog/2017/05/whats-new-in-swift-4-playground/"&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s new in Swift 4&lt;/a&gt;, that also got a mention during one of the WWDC sessions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new &lt;code&gt;Codable&lt;/code&gt; protocol, which hopes to end the war of the JSON parsers; there are a lot of changes to the &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; type, which is now a collection again; Swift 4 supports multi-line literal strings (an announcement that was greeted with lots of applause from the developers), and support for KVC was added (and to make it better, the key paths are strongly typed). However, the best part about Swift 4 is that it is source compatible with Swift 3. Upgrading codebases from Swift 3 to 4 is going to be very easy (&lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Codemine/commit/17cab6b9a3260357ba80c38ff091484ed1d7f80b"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s an example of updating &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Codemin"&gt;Codemine&lt;/a&gt; to the latest Swift version).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="xcode-9"&gt;Xcode 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not Swift 4 that got developers excited at WWDC. The greatest news, for me, at least, was Xcode 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xcode 9 finally brings refactoring for Swift code. Not only that, but the whole source editor was rewritten (in Swift). The source control integration has been improved, there are updates to the build system and Xcode Server comes by default with Xcode 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-laravel.vapor.cloud/image/nstack/translate_values/xcode-3_oHKU9h4bxf.gif"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other noteworthy features are named colours in the asset catalogue, pure vector image support, a main thread checker, a new unexpected behaviour sanitizer, and wireless debugging. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ios-11"&gt;iOS 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to iOS 11, the two new APIs that excited me the most are the new &lt;code&gt;PDFView&lt;/code&gt; and the Drag and Drop. Drag and Drop is really interesting, especially for iPads. There is support for Drag and Drop on iPhones too, but that&amp;rsquo;s only in the same app. For iPad, however, this opens up a lot of possibilities. The whole way of interacting with files and data across multiple applications has been updated. There are a lot of new possibilities for app developers, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see iPad-optimised apps in autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-laravel.vapor.cloud/image/nstack/translate_values/ios_11_drag_and_drop_pltFnWyKjL.gif"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the new &lt;code&gt;PDFViewer&lt;/code&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to not having to use a web view for displaying pdfs; even though that&amp;rsquo;s fast, convenient and it worked, that always seemed a bit like a sub-optimal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-39-s-next"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At WWDC we&amp;rsquo;ve been given a preview of what our next year will be like. We&amp;rsquo;ll get new betas every approx. 2 weeks with the latest updates and changes. In the autumn iOS 11 will be released, and everyone will be able to use the apps we developed during the summer with the latest APIs and features. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Image sources:
- &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/images/wwdc17-og.jpg"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href="http://www.macworld.co.uk/review/ios-apps/ios-11-vs-ios-10-3660096/"&gt;Macworld&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href="https://www.raywenderlich.com/163940/wwdc-2017-initial-impressions"&gt;Ray Wenderlich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Haptic Feedback makes you vibrate!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2017-05-21-haptic-feedback-makes-you-vibrate.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2017-05-21-haptic-feedback-makes-you-vibrate.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-21T23:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This article was first published on the &lt;a href="https://engineering.nodesagency.com/articles/iOS/Haptic-feedback-makes-you-vibrate/"&gt;Nodes Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt; in April 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPhone could vibrate ever since it was launched. And so did almost all the other phones, even from before smartphones were a thing. But Apple took this function further than anyone else, by introducing the Taptic Engine in the Apple Watch, and afterwards in many other products, like the new MacBooks and iPhones. The Taptic Engine provides haptic feedback, more similar to real-life touches than standard vibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with iOS 10, Apple introduced an API for the Taptic Engine, which the developers can use to give haptic feedback to their users. To fully experience the haptic feedback you need an iPhone 7, 7 Plus or newer. Even though the API is introduced in iOS 10, it&amp;rsquo;s only the iPhone 7 and iPhone 7 Plus that support this. On all previous devices, nothing happens when you try to do that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-to-create-haptic-feedback"&gt;How to create haptic feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the new API is super easy. With the &lt;code&gt;UIFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt; you can create haptic feedback with only two lines of code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 7 different types of haptic feedback a developer can use. The only difference between those 7 types of feedback is the vibration pattern. Some of them are subtle, like the selection change, and others are more powerful, like the notification error. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;UIFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt; has 3 subclasses, &lt;code&gt;UISelectionFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;UIImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UINotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt;, and those are the ones a developer should work with. We will showing how to use them further below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the inherent difficulties of showing vibrations through a blog post, we are using the official videos of each type of feedback from Apple&amp;rsquo;s Human Interface Guidelines. You can also run the code &lt;a href="https://github.com/mariusc/Vibrate"&gt;from this repo&lt;/a&gt; on your iPhone 7 or iPhone 7 Plus to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="selection"&gt;Selection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one can be used when the user has to select from multiple discrete values, as he/she scrolls through them. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s used in the &lt;code&gt;UIPickerView&lt;/code&gt;. It feels like a light tap with each selection change. This is not to be used for example when selecting one of 4 radio button choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/selection.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;selectionFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UISelectionFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;selectionFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;selectionChanged&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id="impact"&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact type of feedback is to be used to enhance a visual experience. For example, it can be used in a game when a collision occurs. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find this documented, but I&amp;rsquo;m almost sure that Impact - heavy is the type of feedback that the user feels when a peeked view pops full screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/impact_light.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;lightImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UIImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;light&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;lightImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;impactOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/impact_medium.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;mediumImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UIImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;medium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;mediumImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;impactOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heavy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/impact_heavy.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;heavyImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UIImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;heavy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;heavyImpactFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;impactOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id="notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notification type of feedback should be used to indicate to the user that a task has completed. Depending on the outcome of the task (success, error, warning), the feedback pattern differs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/success.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;successNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UINotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;successNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;notificationOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/warning.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;warningNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UINotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;warningNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;notificationOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;warning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width="400" controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="http://nodesmanager.io/haptic/error.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight swift"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;errorNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kt"&gt;UINotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;errorNotificationFeedbackGenerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;notificationOccurred&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;UIFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt; may have a little latency. If you want to use it to match some sound or visual effects, you can call the &lt;code&gt;prepare()&lt;/code&gt; method on the generator to put the Taptic Engine in a prepared state and reduce the latency. It will stay prepared a few seconds, or until the next feedback is triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="when-to-use-haptic-feedback"&gt;When to use haptic feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw that creating haptic feedback is super easy. However, the complicated part is knowing when and where to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, Apple helps with this, by adding a section on it to the &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/ios/human-interface-guidelines/interaction/feedback/"&gt;Human Interface Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. And we can also learn a lot by looking at where the haptic feedback is used across iOS. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know by now that the Home button isn&amp;rsquo;t an actual button anymore, it&amp;rsquo;s just some very smartly done and well-placed haptic feedback. But that specific pattern doesn&amp;rsquo;t come by default with the new &lt;code&gt;UIFeedbackGenerator&lt;/code&gt;. Other parts of iOS though use the exact types of feedback that the developers can access through the new APIs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when you set an alarm or a timer, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice a light tap whenever the selected time changes. Or when you type, and you hold down a letter on the keyboard to get to the various accents, the same light tap will inform you when you selected a different character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some controls, such as the &lt;code&gt;UIRefreshControl&lt;/code&gt; have the feedback built in, and you will feel a small &amp;ldquo;knock&amp;rdquo; when you pull to refresh a scroll view. Same for zooming in or out a &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt; - zooming too much (either in or out) will also create a &amp;ldquo;knock&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dig deeper, you&amp;rsquo;ll find even more creative use cases of the haptic feedback. For example, sending or viewing an iMessage with fireworks effects will send create &amp;ldquo;thuds&amp;rdquo; for every exploding firework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do haptic feedback right, you need to use it together with some animation or sound effects. Haptic feedback alone will probably feel out of place most of the time. Imagine getting a &lt;code&gt;UINotificationFeedbackType.error&lt;/code&gt; feedback when you show an alert saying that the password you entered is wrong. That would be weird. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Taptic Engine, together with the haptic feedback API has huge potential, and we are looking forward to seeing more creative usages of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/ios/human-interface-guidelines/interaction/feedback/"&gt;iOS Human Interface Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/reference/uikit/uifeedbackgenerator"&gt;UIFeedbackGenerator API Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/mariusc/Vibrate"&gt;Demo project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Serpent - more than just another JSON mapping framework</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2017-04-01-serpent-more-than-just-another-json-mapping-framework.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2017-04-01-serpent-more-than-just-another-json-mapping-framework.html</id>
    <published>2017-04-01T23:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This article was first published on the &lt;a href="https://engineering.nodesagency.com/articles/iOS/Serpent-more-than-just-another-JSON-mapping-framework/"&gt;Nodes Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt;  in March 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/Serpent_icon_MKPKLwKrTM.png" width=30%/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href="https://nodesagency.com"&gt;Nodes&lt;/a&gt;, we develop apps that rely a lot on complex REST APIs. The iOS team needed a fast and fully featured JSON mapping framework.
We had been using our own internal parsing framework for Objective-C for a long time, but when Swift came out we decided to create a new one, in Swift, taking advantage of protocol-oriented programming. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many iterations and a renaming (our JSON mapping framework was previously known as Serializable), we are proud to announce that &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Serpent"&gt;Serpent&lt;/a&gt; has reached version 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="another-json-mapping-framework"&gt;Another JSON mapping framework?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than that. Serpent is &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/SerpentPerformanceComparison#-the-results"&gt;one of the fastest JSON mappers&lt;/a&gt;  out there and has the most features, according to &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/SerpentPerformanceComparison#-feature-comparison"&gt;our analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nodes-ios/SerpentPerformanceComparison/master/chart.png" width=100%/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe you only have to parse and map small JSONs, and you don&amp;rsquo;t care that much about the time it takes. But what about the time it takes to write the mapping code? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a tool that goes hand in hand with Serpent: with &lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/ModelBoiler_1281_Hkq7ey3ZGo.png" width=4%/&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Model Boiler&lt;/strong&gt; you only have to declare the properties on your model, and the parsing code will be generated for you, potentially saving you hours of work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src = "https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/ModelBoiler_5S0fTmSARI.gif"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="but-why-build-a-new-one"&gt;But why build a new one?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are lots of other JSON mapping frameworks out there. But when we started developing Serpent, there was only SwiftyJSON, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly what we wanted. So we needed to build our own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2016, we moved the project to a &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Serpent"&gt;public GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; and began developing in the open. At the same time, we started using this framework in all our apps, and at the moment, we can say that &lt;strong&gt;Serpent is used in apps with more than 1.3 million monthly users&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="working-with-serpent"&gt;Working with Serpent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built Serpent to make developers&amp;rsquo; life as easy as possible when creating models. So we also built a few goodies around Serpent, which allow the developer to save a lot of time when creating the models for the app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="serpent-xcode-file-template"&gt;&lt;img src = "https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/TemplateIcon_ma6gVMOOZ7.png" width=4%/&gt; Serpent Xcode File Template&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made the &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/SerpentXcodeFileTemplate"&gt;Serpent Xcode File Template&lt;/a&gt;, which adds a new file template for Xcode. No more typing &lt;code&gt;import Serpent&lt;/code&gt; manually. It sounds small, but when you have to create 10-20 models, it saves you from a lot of annoyance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f6a75647a614a5a2e706e67_JSsVywYm5H.png" width=50%/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="model-boiler"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/ModelBoiler_1281_Hkq7ey3ZGo.png" width=4%/&gt; Model Boiler&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most annoying part when working with JSONs in Swift is typing all the parsing code. We made a tool that works with Serpent that does that for you. The &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/ModelBoiler"&gt;Model Boiler&lt;/a&gt; is a small macOS app that lives in your mac&amp;rsquo;s menu bar. In Xcode (or your favourite editor), select the code for the model and its properties, and press a keyboard shortcut, and the Model Boiler will generate the necessary code for parsing to your Clipboard. You can just paste the parsing code in your model. And that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src = "https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/modelboiler_QFktJAlXOv.gif" width=40%/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with the Xcode file template and with the Model Boiler, Serpent is (in our opinion) the easiest and most pleasant to use JSON mapping framework for Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="why-serpent"&gt;Why Serpent?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a short list of some of the advantages that Serpent has:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its own &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/SerpentXcodeFileTemplate"&gt;Xcode file template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its own code generator: &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/ModelBoiler"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/nstack/translate_values/ModelBoiler_1281_Hkq7ey3ZGo.png" width=4%/&gt; Model Boiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best balance between speed and features. We did &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/SerpentPerformanceComparison"&gt;the tests&lt;/a&gt; and we compared it to some of the most popular JSON mapping frameworks out there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://codecov.io/github/nodes-ios/Serpent"&gt;100% test coverage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carthage, CocoaPods and Swift Package Manager support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different versions of it are used in apps used by more than 1.3 million users every month (based on analytics data for some of our apps).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re really proud to be able to release the 1.0 version of Serpent. The biggest thanks go to all the &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Serpent/graphs/contributors"&gt;contributors that made it possible&lt;/a&gt;. We hope more developers find Serpent useful and give it a try in their apps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serpent is &lt;a href="https://github.com/nodes-ios/Serpent"&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;. If you find bugs or have ideas for new features, you&amp;rsquo;re more than welcome to contribute to Serpent. And if you really like what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, check out the &lt;a href="https://www.nodesagency.com/careers/"&gt;Nodes careers page&lt;/a&gt; and join us to make awesome things together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding code signing for iOS apps</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2016-11-27-understanding-code-signing-for-ios-apps.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2016-11-27-understanding-code-signing-for-ios-apps.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-27T20:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This article was first published on the &lt;a href="https://engineering.nodesagency.com/articles/iOS/Understanding-code-signing-for-iOS-apps/"&gt;Nodes Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt;  in October 2016.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an iOS developer, most likely you&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with code signing. And if you&amp;rsquo;re a junior iOS developer, you might&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit overwhelmed by everything going on in the &amp;ldquo;Certificates, Identifiers &amp;amp; Profiles&amp;rdquo; section of the developer portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/baas/translate_values/hbikk_ospmSpNLyW.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this article is to help junior iOS developers understand code signing on a higher level. This will not be a step-by-step tutorial on how to code sign your app. Ideally, after reading this article, you will be able to code sign your app without following any tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to go into lower level details, but we will talk a bit about asymmetric cryptography. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="asymmetric-cryptography"&gt;Asymmetric cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minimum you need to know is that asymmetric cryptography uses a &lt;strong&gt;public key&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;private key&lt;/strong&gt;. The users have to keep their private key for themselves, but they can share the public key. And using those public and private keys, a user can prove that he is indeed himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good high-level explanation of asymmetric cryptography can be found &lt;a href="https://blog.vrypan.net/2013/08/28/public-key-cryptography-for-non-geeks/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to know implementation details or the math behind this, you can find them online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="app-id"&gt;App ID&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The App ID is the unique identifier of your app. It consists of a team id, generated by Apple (you don&amp;rsquo;t have any control over it) and your app&amp;rsquo;s bundle id (&lt;code&gt;com.youcompany.yourapp&lt;/code&gt;, for example). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can also be wildcard App IDs: &lt;code&gt;com.yourcompany.*&lt;/code&gt;. Those will match on multiple bundle ids. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, you will have an explicit App ID, not a wildcard one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="certificates"&gt;Certificates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have probably already noticed that in order to create a certificate in Apple&amp;rsquo;s developer portal, you need to upload a Certificate Signing Request. You can generate this CSR from the Keychain, and this CSR contains a private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on the developer portal, you can create a certificate using this CSR. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be multiple types of certificates. The most common are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development (iOS App Development) - You need those to run your app on a device from Xcode. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distribution (App Store and Ad Hoc) - You need those to be able to distribute your app through the App Store or Ad Hoc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APNS (Apple Push Notification Service)  - You need those to be able to send push notifications to your app. Unlike Development or Distribution certificates, APNS certificates are associated with an App ID. There can be 2 types of APNS certificates, for development - Apple Push Notification service SSL (Sandbox), and for production - Apple Push Notification service SSL (Sandbox &amp;amp; Production). You need to create both of them if you want push notifications to work on both debug and distribution builds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="devices"&gt;Devices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add up to 100 devices per product family per membership year to your account. 100 iPhones, 100 iPads, 100 iPod Touch, 100 Apple Watches and 100 Apple TVs. To add a device to your account, you need to add its unique device ID. You can easily find that in Xcode, or (a bit more complicated) in iTunes. A detailed guide on how to add devices to your account can be found &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/IDEs/Conceptual/AppDistributionGuide/MaintainingProfiles/MaintainingProfiles.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40012582-CH30-SW10"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="provisioning-profiles"&gt;Provisioning profiles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provisioning profile is what associates an App ID with a certificate and, for development or ad hoc distribution, with some devices. You create the provisioning profiles on the Apple developer portal and you download them in Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have created all these, you can then go to Xcode, add your certificates, refresh your provisioning profiles and then select the provisioning profile you want. You can then select the desired signing identity (based on the certificate associated with it) from that provisioning profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="f-a-q"&gt;F.A.Q.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years working in iOS development, I&amp;rsquo;ve asked and I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked many questions about code signing. Here are some of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;: I have downloaded the provisioning profiles and certificates from the developer portal, but I can&amp;rsquo;t sign the app.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes, because you don&amp;rsquo;t have the private key, the one that was in the certificate signing request. Most likely, another team member created those certificates and provisioning profiles before. You can get the private key from the original developer, revoke the certificate and generate a new one (which will break all provisioning profiles associated with that certificate, but not any App Store apps using those) or create a new one if possible (currently, there&amp;rsquo;s a maximum of 3 distribution certificates allowed per account).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;: What about the push certificates? I want my app to receive push notifications. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t I create a provisioning profile that uses the APNS certificate?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No. When you create an APNS (Apple Push Notification Service) certificate, you associate that with an App ID. So, first you have your CSR, then you create a new APNS certificate with that CSR, download it, open it in Keychain and export it as .p12, which you later upload to your push notification provider. The .p12 file will know that it&amp;rsquo;s associated with that app, and it will send pushes to that app only. That&amp;rsquo;s also a reason why you can&amp;rsquo;t associate an APNS certificate with a wildcard App ID (com.youcompany.*). The push notification server needs to know to which app it sends the notifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;: I bought a new mac, what should I export from the keychain of my old mac for all the code signing to work on the new one?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: You would probably want all your keychain to be exported to the new mac. You can do that by following &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/PH20120?locale=en_US"&gt;these steps&lt;/a&gt;. But if you want to export one certificate, make sure you also export its private key. In the Keychain, you have to be able to expand the certificate by pressing on the arrow next to it, and you should see a key. Those certificates are the ones that can be exported as .p12 files. Otherwise, they&amp;rsquo;ll be exported as .cer, without a private key, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty much useless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;: My iOS distribution certificate expired, will my app still work?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: When your certificate expires, the provisioning profiles using that certificate will become invalid. On App Store, the app will still work as long as you&amp;rsquo;re enrolled in the development program. All the ad hoc builds signed with that certificate won&amp;rsquo;t work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;: My APNS certificate expired, what happens now?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to send push notifications to the app anymore. This can be fixed by creating a new APNS certificate associated with that App ID, downloading it, exporting its .p12 and uploading it to your push notification service provider. No need for an app update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key points I want to highlight about code signing are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each app has an &lt;strong&gt;App ID&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to have the &lt;strong&gt;private keys&lt;/strong&gt; for all the certificates you use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;debug provisioning profile&lt;/strong&gt; associates your development certificate with your App ID and the devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;ad hoc provisioning profile&lt;/strong&gt; associates your distribution certificate with your App ID and the devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;app store provisioning profile&lt;/strong&gt; associates your distribution certificate with your App ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For push notifications, create an &lt;strong&gt;APNS certificate&lt;/strong&gt; associated with your App ID, then download it, export it as .p12 and upload the .p12 to your push notification service provider; if you want push notifications both on debug and production builds, you have to create 2 APNS certificates, one for development and one for production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding these will help you understand code signing and save you a lot of time in the end. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d1gwekl0pol55k.cloudfront.net/image/baas/translate_values/success_YGu5HHLDK6.jpg" width = 50% /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-reading"&gt;Further reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.objc.io/issues/17-security/inside-code-signing/"&gt;Inside code signing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/code-signing/"&gt;Code Signing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/ios-os-x-development/ios-code-signing-provisioning-in-a-nutshell-d5b247760bef"&gt;iOS Code Signing &amp;amp; Provisioning in a Nutshell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Being more efficient in Xcode - Part 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2016-10-09-being-more-efficient-in-xcode-part-2.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2016-10-09-being-more-efficient-in-xcode-part-2.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-09T10:25:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T20:13:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my second article in the &amp;ldquo;Being more efficient in Xcode&amp;rdquo; series. The first part, which you can read &lt;a href="http://mariusc.github.io/2016-08-29-being-more-efficient-in-xcode-part-1.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, was focused on keyboard shortcuts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the keyboard shortcuts, there are other tips and tricks an iOS developer should know, to be able to improve his productivity when using Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="breakpoints"&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good idea to add an &amp;lsquo;All exceptions&amp;rsquo; breakpoint. This way, when your app crashes, you&amp;rsquo;ll get stopped exactly when that happens and you can see the whole backtrace and debug the problem more easily. A good idea is to also add a debugger command action on that breakpoint to print the exception you&amp;rsquo;re encountering. Open the breakpoint in the Breakpoint navigator, right click your All exception breakpoint, press Edit, press Add action and add this debugger command &lt;code&gt;po $arg1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts/backFwd.png" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, sometimes (especially if you&amp;rsquo;re using Swift), you might notice that your app always stops in the AppDelegate when launching it. You can manually continue over that, but it&amp;rsquo;s still annoying. To stop that from happening, you can edit your exceptions breakpoint to only stop for Objective-C exceptions, ignoring other types of exceptions such as C++ ones. Depending on your project, this could be a bad idea, but in most cases it will be fine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts2/objc_exceptions_breakopint.png" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use breakpoints to print variables: just add a po command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="editor"&gt;Editor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we all know and we&amp;rsquo;ve all been complaining about, there&amp;rsquo;s no refactoring in Swift. There is, however, a better-than-nothing alternative, which in some cases can be used instead of rename-refactoring. Select a variable (double click on it), go to Editor - Edit all in scope. Enter the new name and it will be renamed everywhere in the current scope. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts2/EditAllInScope.gif" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name says, this only edits in the current scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another command that affects only the current scope is &amp;#39;Fix all in scope&amp;rsquo;. This makes the changes suggested by Xcode for all the warnings and errors. This also only affects the current scope. And sometimes, Xcode&amp;rsquo;s suggestions are not exactly what you had in mind. Nevertheless, this command can still be useful sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts2/FixAllInScope.gif" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="code-structure"&gt;Code structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the Document items list. Open the list (either press on it, or use the shortcut control - 6) and you can see all the classes, extensions, methods, etc in your file. If you start typing, it will begin filtering them in a way similar to quick open, but it will search for entries inside the currently open file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts2/ListOfMethods.gif" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also a very good idea to use &lt;code&gt;//MARK:&lt;/code&gt; in your source. This allows you to organize the methods and other items in your code in a better way. They&amp;rsquo;re also visible in the Document items list. And also, if for example you have a &lt;code&gt;//MARK: - UITableViewDelegate&lt;/code&gt; you can command - click on the &lt;code&gt;UITableViewDelegate&lt;/code&gt; and it will take you to the UITableView interface, where you can see all the available methods and their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="interface-builder"&gt;Interface builder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one last tip about interface builder. Did you ever need, for example, to move a button on top of another view, but not make it a subview of that view? By default, when you drop a button over a view, IB will make the button a subview of that view and you will also lose all its positioning constraints. But if you press &lt;strong&gt;⌘&lt;/strong&gt; while dropping the button, it will not be a subview, but a sibling of that view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/XcodeShortcuts2/Cmd.gif" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of shortcuts in Xcode, and lots of things you can do to increase your speed when using it. The important thing is to take them one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
