<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Marius Constantinescu</title>
  <subtitle>Tech blog</subtitle>
  <id>https://mariusc.github.io/</id>
  <link href="https://mariusc.github.io/"/>
  <link href="https://mariusc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-04-12T19:01:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>My first iOS app</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2016-04-12-my-first-ios-app.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2016-04-12-my-first-ios-app.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T19:01:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I read Becky Hansmeyer&amp;rsquo;s article &lt;a href="http://beckyhansmeyer.com/2016/04/09/we-all-have-to-start-somewhere/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;We all have to start somewhere&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, and it surprised me. Becky says she only knows one person in real life that develops iOS apps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first contact with iOS development was during my BSc. studies. We were a bunch of students and a passionate teaching assistant, and we were learning iOS development on our own, outside of the university curriculum, following Paul Hegarty&amp;rsquo;s Stanford CS193P course on iTunes U. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing that there are iOS developers who only know one other iOS developer in real life made me realise that I was fortunate to not be alone in my journey. This makes me put even more value on our great iOS community, on all the knowledge that is shared out there through blog posts, video talks, open source apps, libraries and frameworks, and also on all the conferences and meetups that enable developers to meet each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding Becky&amp;rsquo;s challenge, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say what my very first iOS app was. The very first iOS app I wrote and compiled was probably a calculator, one of the first homeworks on Paul Hegarty course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project I did on my own (without it being an assignment) was a Cocos2D game, inspired by the &lt;a href="http://www.helicoptergame.net/"&gt;2d flash helicopter game&lt;/a&gt;. The user could control a bird and had to avoid flying too high, too low or crashing into baloons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/birdie.png" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the graphic resources used in the game were found online. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they were in the public domain or not, but I never wanted to publish the game, I just wanted to learn. That was also the moment when I realised it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to create iOS games without also having a graphics designer in your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if it comes to the first app I worked on that made it to the App Store, then it must be &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/georeporter/id487304759?mt=8"&gt;GeoReporter&lt;/a&gt;, my Google Summer of Code 2013 project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we all start somewhere. Not everybody starts in the same place. But fortunately, we have lots of examples in the community showing that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter where you start as long as you love what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and you&amp;rsquo;re doing your best&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How I got my first job as an iOS developer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2016-02-03-how-i-got-my-first-job-as-an-ios-developer.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2016-02-03-how-i-got-my-first-job-as-an-ios-developer.html</id>
    <published>2016-02-03T19:48:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/orta"&gt;@orta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s excellent &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about how to get your first job as an iOS developer, and that made me think a bit about the process through which I got my first iOS job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, I took part in the Google Summer of Code as a member of the City of Bloomington organization. My task was to work on their open source iOS app for non-emergency issue reporting. If I remember correctly, that was the only proposal I sent, because I really wanted to work as an iOS developer and that position in the City of Bloomington organization was the only one that interested me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that, I had some very basic iOS experience: I watched some of Paul Hegarty&amp;rsquo;s course at Stanford on iTunes U and my bachelor thesis project was an iPad app. Besides that, I also had a pretty solid background in Computer Science. But the GSoC experience was when I actually dived head first into iOS programming. At the end of the summer, I had 3 months of iOS experience, some pretty good open source contribution, a nice thing to add to my iOS developer portfolio and 2 recommendations from my GSoC mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After GSoC, I started looking for a part time job as an iOS developer in Copenhagen. Now, good iOS developers are hard to find, but in the autumn of 2013, not many companies were interested in a junior iOS developer who could only work part time because he wanted to finish his MSc studies. Looking over the &lt;a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/30/iOS-Junior-Interviews/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, I realize now that I went through almost all the phases described there, so I can take them one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Readiness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience, I knew I still had a lot to learn, but I had worked on 2 apps before, I could find may way around Xcode, I had a good background and I could learn fast. I also wasn&amp;rsquo;t afraid to admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t know something and I showed a genuine interest and curiosity about the things I didn&amp;rsquo;t know. With that in mind, I tried not to create false expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lookout&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some job sites in Denmark, but there weren&amp;rsquo;t many iOS developer positions advertised there. Also, they were all full time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told that in Denmark, the practice of sending unsolicited applications is quite common, so I gave it a try. I started looking for companies that were doing iOS development and sent unsolicited applications to the ones that interested me the most. The problem with unsolicited applications is that they take a lot of time to be replied to. I once got a reply 2 months after I sent the application. This whole process takes a lot of time. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have too many irons in the fire, so I started by sending one application to a company, and then waiting for it to reply. I got a reply after one week and I was invited for a coffee (which I mistakenly confused for an interview). The meeting was scheduled for the next week and, since they didn&amp;rsquo;t have an available position at the moment, I was basically at the same place where I started, but 2 weeks later. After that, I started sending unsolicited applications to 2 companies at the same time, so I could hopefully speed up the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intro email&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably where I didn&amp;rsquo;t do enough, and it could well be the reason most of my unsolicited applications didn&amp;rsquo;t get any replies. My emails were quite short, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bother the reader (I still consider this a plus), but they were mostly about me. Somewhere along the lines of &amp;ldquo;I am a student, I did an iOS app in the GSoC programme, I want to work part time as an iOS developer&amp;rdquo;. Not much or nothing about why I sent this email to &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company. And that&amp;rsquo;s a pitty, because I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t send an email to all of them at once, but I had a list of companies, with pluses and minuses for each and I had them sorted according to my preference for them. If I had done this the right way, probably I would&amp;rsquo;ve got more replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coffee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of getting coffee ☕️ with potential employers was new to me. So new that I actually considered an invitation for coffee to be an interview, which made me quite disappointed when I realised that there were no positions available. It all makes sense now, but back then it didn&amp;rsquo;t. I got invited for coffee with 2 different companies, and I actually enjoyed meeting people that do what I also wanted to do. I had some great meetings and I had hopes for a potential job interview with one of the companies, either in January or in the spring of 2014. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;coffee&amp;rdquo; was actually how I found my first iOS dev job. But since this is Denmark, that &amp;ldquo;coffee&amp;rdquo; was actually a beer 🍺. I was participating in the weekly NSCoderNight meetings, some casual get-togethers for iOS developers. That&amp;rsquo;s where I met &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KasperWelner"&gt;Kasper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jeghedderjohnny"&gt;Johnny&lt;/a&gt;, who are now my colleagues. They were looking for a senior iOS developer to join them at &lt;a href="http://www.nodesagency.com"&gt;Nodes&lt;/a&gt;. I had actually seen the job announcement for that position, but decided to ignore it since they needed a full time senior developer, while I was a junior who could only work part time. We talked a bit, each of us about the projects we were working on at the moment, I remember I showed a small demo and also a bit of code, and from there, things moved very quickly. Next day, Kasper contacted me saying that they talked to their CTO and if I was interested, they were open to a part time position as well. I was interested, I had an interview the following day and I started on Monday of the following week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview went on really well and the process was faster than I expected it to be (but that was probably a one time thing). First they told me about the company, then I told them about myself, about my background, studies, experience and current and future plans. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember being asked anything technical, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s because we talked a lot about code at NSCoderNight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of hours after the interview ended I had been offered the job. I was probably lucky, because the company really needed to hire developers, but I like to see it as the universe&amp;rsquo;s way to make up for all the months of sending unsolicited applications with no reply 🙃.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a happy ending for me, because I still work there (full time now) and I really enjoy what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. But this thing took a lot of time: I started my job on March 10, 2014. Between September and March, I sent a lot of unsolicited applications, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to some coffee meetings, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a couple of interviews which didn&amp;rsquo;t really work out, I went to a few meetups and I met a good number of the iOS developers in Copenhagen. And most importantly, I kept working on my own small iOS projects in that period and I kept learning. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UIViewContentModes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-29-uiviewcontentmodes.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-29-uiviewcontentmodes.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-29T10:46:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a very simple and visual post, showing the differences in what an image looks like using different &lt;code&gt;UIViewContentMode&lt;/code&gt;s. It&amp;rsquo;s something I really needed in my early days as an iOS developer. So a couple of years later, I decided to make this visual guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll use this &lt;a href="http://cache-graphicslib.viator.com/graphicslib/thumbs674x446/12254/SITours/day-trip-to-sinaia-from-bucharest-including-peles-castle-in-sinaia-211359.jpg"&gt;image here&lt;/a&gt; of the Peleș castle in Romania:
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/peles_castle.jpg" class="img-responsive"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will show it in a square 200 x 200 &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt;, going through all the possible &lt;code&gt;UIViewContentMode&lt;/code&gt;s. The 1x asset used in this project was sized to 224 x 148, with the @2x and @3x being scaled proportionally. For a better understanding, the background color of the &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt; was set to black and &lt;code&gt;clipsToBounds&lt;/code&gt; was set to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. Here are the results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Scale_to_fill.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Aspect_fit.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Aspect_fill_no_clip.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Redraw.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Center.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Top.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Bottom.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Left.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Right.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Top_left.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Top_right.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Bottom_left.png" width=33%/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src = "img/blogposts/inline/Bottom_right.png" class="img-responsive" width=33%/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aspect fit&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Aspect fill&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Center&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Top&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Bottom&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Left&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Right&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Top left&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Top right&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Bottom left&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Bottom right&lt;/code&gt; are non-distorting content modes, they keep the original aspect ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aspect fit&lt;/code&gt; will scale the image while keeping the aspect ratio in order to fit the whole image in the &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt;. So its biggest side will fit perfectly in the view, and its smallest side will be scaled proportionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aspect fill&lt;/code&gt; will scale the image while keeping the aspect ratio in order to fill the whole &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt;. So its smallest side will fit perfectly in the view, and its biggest side will be scaled proportionally. This one will be bigger than the view, so depending on the &lt;code&gt;clipsToBounds&lt;/code&gt; value, it will either go out of the &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt;, or show only the portion that fits in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Scale to fill&lt;/code&gt; will scale both sides of the image to fill the entire view. This will obviously change the aspect ratio and stretch the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though &lt;code&gt;Redraw&lt;/code&gt; has the same effect here as &lt;code&gt;Scale to fill&lt;/code&gt;, behind the scenes they are very different. &lt;code&gt;Redraw&lt;/code&gt; forces a redraw of the view (calls &lt;code&gt;drawRect:&lt;/code&gt; in your view) in response to geometry changes (for example, a change of the frame&amp;rsquo;s value). It&amp;rsquo;s not generally used, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to use it on standard system views. In this case, the result is the same because we used &lt;code&gt;Redraw&lt;/code&gt; on a standard view, with the default implementation of &lt;code&gt;drawRect:&lt;/code&gt; (which appears to be using the &lt;code&gt;Scale to fill&lt;/code&gt; mode).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making an app for tvOS - part 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-09-making-an-app-for-tvos-part-1.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-09-making-an-app-for-tvos-part-1.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-09T21:10:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As curious iOS developers, having had the Apple TV for a week, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ruxandranistor"&gt;@RuxandraNistor&lt;/a&gt; and I decided that it’s time to try and make an Apple TV app. We didn’t have an idea for an app, but we knew we wanted to make one.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being two iOS developers with limited time for side projects, a lack of experience when it comes to digital design and a strong desire to not make any APIs or backend development, it was quite hard for us to come up with a good idea for an app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we had no content, we thought that we could either build a game, or find an external API to give us content. The one thing we always kept coming back to was that it’s very hard and annoying to input text in an Apple TV app. &lt;em&gt;So whatever app we were building, if we showed content to the user, that content had to be browsable, and not searchable.&lt;/em&gt; So I could say goodbye to my idea of making a beer journal (like Vivino, but for beers), an iOS project I started and never finished. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I like tennis, I’d like an app that gives me real time scores for tennis games, ATP and WTA rankings, tournament draws and results and all other kind of tennis news. But all that content was not easy to find in a way that made it easy for us to show it on the Apple TV. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we thought that the idea was to complex: we just wanted to make a simple app to see what’s up with tvOS. So we thought of making 9GAG for Apple TV. We were very pleased with the idea, until we realised that there’s no official API for 9GAG, nor an RSS feed for it. So we looked into other similar websites (BoredPanda, BuzzFeed, etc), with no success: none of them had a good API or RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the end, we chose to make a simple game. Three hours later, we had our first prototype running. Now we need to add more complexity, make it pretty and make it catchy. More about that in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Writing Challenge</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-01-writing-challenge.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2015-11-01-writing-challenge.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-01T18:26:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s this thing I found out about on Twitter that people call “&lt;em&gt;NaBloWriMo&lt;/em&gt;”. It actually is a derived version of “&lt;em&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/em&gt;”, which stands for National Novel Writing Month. Shortly, &lt;em&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/em&gt; is a challenge where people have to write daily for one month, and in the end have a 50.000 words fictional novel. I didn’t know this exists, but I found of its other version, “&lt;em&gt;NaBloWriMo&lt;/em&gt;” (ok, I’ve got to admit, I think this name sounds silly) from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mennenia/status/660769278715633664"&gt;Maxim Cramer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules I’ll follow during this challenge are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;publish at least one article per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One article per week isn’t very much, but compared to my usual writing frequency, it’s a lot. And in the end, the goal of this is to create a habit for writing, not just to add 4 more articles to my blog. Because, as &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjjvnrqDjpM"&gt;Ash Furrow says&lt;/a&gt;, sharing your knowledge makes you a better developer in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to hoping I can finish the challenge🍷!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One week with the Apple Watch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mariusc.github.io/2015-07-03-one-week-with-the-apple-watch.html"/>
    <id>https://mariusc.github.io/2015-07-03-one-week-with-the-apple-watch.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-03T13:33:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-03T12:51:16+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Constantinescu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we got the Apple Watch delivered at Nodes, I was very happy and I was hoping that I would get to use it for a while, to see how it is and what it can do. I got to try it for about one week, and my first impression wasn&amp;rsquo;t very flattering for the company in Cupertino. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the features that are advertised so hard by Apple didn&amp;rsquo;t really impress me. Yes, I could get all the notifications on my wrist too, not only on the phone. The important question is if I really want that. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want to feel a tap on my wrist every time a work colleague assigns me a Trello ticket, or when another recruiter wants to connect with me on LinkedIn. And yes, I know I can disable some or all of the notifications, but if I do that, what am I left with? An overpriced watch that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really look that good and that needs to be charged daily. However, towards the end of my week wearing the Apple Watch, I also found some nice features that I really appreciated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When at home, I usually leave my phone in a room and don&amp;rsquo;t carry it with me around the house or in the yard. This means that I can&amp;rsquo;t hear it when it rings. However, with the Apple Watch, this problem is solved, because the watch vibrates when I get a call. This is probably the feature that I appreciated the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I really liked about the watch was the glance in which I could ping the iPhone. It sometimes (more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like to) happens to me to forget where I left my iPhone. One way to find it would be to ask someone to give me a call, but if the phone is on silent mode, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t help. I could also log in to iCloud and use Find my iPhone to make it ring. But that&amp;rsquo;s a bit more hassle than I&amp;rsquo;d like to. Using the Apple Watch, I can ping my iPhone in just 2 taps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very cool thing is the way it vibrates. The taptic engine gives a much more human touch to it, instead of the artificial vibration we are used to. This somehow reminds me of the power LED on the MacBook Pros, that instead of flashing intermitently and mecanical, at regular intervals, it mimics the breathing frequency of a human being. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice touch which I really appreciated. As a downside, after not wearing the watch anymore, I thought I felt a couple of ghost taps on my wrist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conclusion for the Apple Watch is that it&amp;rsquo;s a decent device, with some features that I find as nice to have, some that I don&amp;rsquo;t need and one that I absolutely loved. The downsides are the huge price, the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of how it looks and that in order to wear one, I have to give up my current watch, which has sentimental value to me, and it&amp;rsquo;s not something I&amp;rsquo;m prepared to let go easily. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not going to get an Apple Watch soon. But who knows what future models will bring?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
